

 $\times$ 

suvamdawn94@gmail.com

(+91) 7407620534 / (+91) 8436758250



Bangalore, India



suvamdawn94.wixsite.com/s

#### in

https://www.linkedin.com/i n/suvamdawn/



github.com/Suvam-Dawn

# **LANGUAGES**

Bengali



English



Hindi



# **SUVAM DAWN**

Software Engineer

Experienced as a Software Engineer with vast IT experience. Skills include Mobile App Development, Database-Management, and Handling, Server-Side Management, Website Design and Development, Analytical thinking, and creative problem-solving. Also able to apply customer service concepts to IT to improve the user experience for clients, employees, and administration.

# **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree (MCA)
Presidency College, Bangalore

08/2015 – 06/2018 Courses

Computer Application

### **SKILLS**



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Software Engineer**

GeekSynergy Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

08/2018 – Present Responsibilities:-

- Managing a client's requirements, system analysis, and functional specifications.
- Defining best practices for project support, & documentation.
- Actively participates & engages with development team & testing team to provide quality services, system stability, and best solutions.
- Proposed solutions for complex architectural challenges for new features.
- Testing, problem-solving, troubleshooting, & debugging of the applications.
- Managing, & integrated app-based solutions with databases, backend, security, data facilitation, file systems, & cloud based systems.
- Implement company SEO plans, and create road map for accomplishments.
- Monitor effectiveness of SEO, and marketing programmers in terms of traffic.

#### Intern

GeekSynergy Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

02/2018 - 07/2018 Responsibilities:-

- Android UI & UX design.
- Testing, problem-solving, troubleshooting, and debugging of the applications.

75.87%

# **Highlighted Projects**

#### PayHub

PayHub is a payment processing platform for Correspondent banks and IFL Partners. It is a private cloud-based platform that helps automate the incoming payment processing for our partners and helps deliver the payments to local clearing channels within the country. This system can accept different kinds of payment files, like SWIFT, XML, XLS, and Excel, etc. & able to convert in different formats.

### Technology:-

- React.js
- Spring boot & Micro Services
- MongoDB
- Rabbitmq
- Postgresql

#### Responsibilities:-

- UI & UX design for end-user.
- Dynamic template creation for UI.
- Help to manage database, and backend to improve data manipulation, security and data facilitation.
- Different payment messages processing and conversion including micro service creation.
- Proposed solutions for complex architectural challenges for new features.
- Actively participates & engages with development team & testing team to provide quality services, system stability, and best solutions.

### Digitour Android Application & Website

Digitour is a digital tourism app with taking care of guidance to tourists on a subscription basis which is handling and monitor by the Karnataka Government.

#### Technology:-

- Android
- Rest API
- Google Map
- Google Authentication (Gmail & Phone Base Authentication)
- KRPano
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Html, CSS & Bootstrap
- JQuery, Ajax

#### Responsibilities:-

- UI & UX design for end-user and third party users.
- KRPano integration in both the end (Android & Web).
- Google Authentication integration.
- API integration and management.
- Manual testing, problem-solving, troubleshooting, and debugging of the applications.
- Google Map integration to provide fixable services to the user.
- Maintaining the user's subscription and subscription history.

Website: - https://dgtour.in/

### Building-Survey App (Android Application)

Building-Survey App is an android application which is helping to manage, save, and keep track of building details.

# Technology:-

- Android
- Rest API
- KML & GeoJSON
- Google Map

SQLite

#### Responsibilities:-

- UI & UX design.
- API integration and management.
- Plot GeoJSON into Google Map and functionality implementation.
- Manual testing, problem-solving, troubleshooting, and debugging of the application.

## WinkWash Sales Executive App & Customer App (Android Application)

- The WinkWash Sales Executive App is a react-native application which that automates the pickup and delivery process in laundry services. The app act as a mobile Point-Of-Sale (POS) system that can be used by delivery guys to place order, schedule pickup, and delivery.
- WinkWash Customer Application is an android application for end-user which is a complete laundry software solution that takes care of booking, pick up, delivery, order management, payments, and also has its own e-wallet.

#### Technology:-

- React-native
- Rest API
- FCM Notification

#### Responsibilities:-

- UI & UX design.
- FCM notification integration.
- API integration and management.
- Payment gateway integration.
- Manual testing, problem-solving, troubleshooting and debugging of the application.

Download (WinkWash Customer App): - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.geeksynergy.winkwashuser

#### WinkWash Admin Panel & Website

WinkWash Admin Panel is a web application which is helping to manage and keep track entire business process, customer, and sales executives.

#### Technology:-

- Express.js
- MongoDB
- Html, CSS & Bootstrap
- JQuery, Ajax

#### Responsibilities:-

- UI & UX design for dashboard and other modules.
- Datatable(client-side & server-side) integration in user-side.
- Managing requirement gathering, system analysis, and functional specifications.
- Help to manage database and backend to improve data manipulation, security and data facilitation.

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the details furnished above are true to the best of my knowledge.	
PLACE: BANGALORE	SUVAM DAWN